so the other week I showed you how to do
super easy Italian gelato in your Ninja
creamy using half and half (10% cream if you
will) today I'm going to show you how to do
American style ice cream with 18% fat coffee
cream condensed milk and an extract [Music]
Yeah I love really easy ways to make ice cream
I I also love the super ultra complicated ways
of making it cuz hey that's what I do but the
half and half gelato was delicious super easy
and that's kind of what you want especially
for a creamy you want recipes that are going
to be super quick but you want recipes that are
going to be good not the junk that's elsewhere so
we're going to do something along the same kind
of lines that we did with the half and half but
we're going to use this, the 18% coffee cream. Now
this recipe is good in North America and the UK.
UK your single cream is 18% milk fat so with that
in mind ....adjustment, let's get on and do it
So we need a couple of things obviously we need
our cream we need our condensed milk one of
these corn syrup golden syrup whatever it's not
essential but using it creates a more balanced
recipe it gives you a better freezing point
and the right amount of sugar and an extract
last time I used lemon and hazelnut this time
I'm going to use coffee and almond extract is
nilson Macy needs to be an alcohol-based extract
okay otherwise this won't be balanced a balanced
recipe means that it's designed and all the
macros line up so that it tastes perfect the
texture is perfect and also you don't have to
respin it in your machine if you don't eat the
whole tub straight away you can spin it put it
in the freezer and then a week later take it out
and just eat it all right so I'll put the cut
measurements up on the screen like I normally
do but for now as I am British I use
grams it's so much easier to do science
based food with grams a gram scale why
because when you get down to to little
tiny measurements especially with stabilizers
there are none in here you kind of need that
to be exact but we don't need worry about
that today so let's let's get our our cream
out we need 3 no we don't need 300, we
need 635g of our cream oh exactly 635,
leave that there this has no other additives to it
it's just milk cream try and get that if you can
a lot of the dairy has you know the stabilizers
in which isn't so bad but it's better to be in
control of those stabilizers yourself rather than
within the products that you buy. One entire can,
this is I always say this... this is 300ml
it will give you 350g of condensed milk.
so lick spoon
and we need an invert sugar, corn syrup,
golden syrup, glucose syrup any of those
is fine I'm going to use golden syrup
today because...... I can! 10 whole grams,
doesn't sound like a lot makes a big difference
and our extracts I'm going to do what I did
last time I'm going to split it up let's
get rid of that so let's get a whisk out
don't worry about air bubbles on the top
you can't you can't um whip this there's
not enough milk fat in it so what did I say
split it let's get our tubs put this in the
fridge and let's split it between the
two like so and armored extract I'm
going to start doing some videos on how
to make your own extracts two whole G of extract
nearly out exactly the same for coffee like
so mini whisk and we're just going
to do [Music] that and do that
nice that's it Lids
on into the freezer till it's completely Frozen
so I right overnight is best just occurred to me
that I said 2 G of each extract it's not it's
4 G of each extract okay important right it's
been in overnight we're going to do the coffee
one today so the Almond one is going to be used
in another video so if you want to see what I
do with that like And subscribe um we're going
to yeah like I said we're going to do coffee so
this used the this used the Nelson Macy coffee
extract I've had this for years it it just lasts
and last and lasts and it smells pretty strong
it's uh can't get a lid back on what we're
going to do is we're going to do coffee ice
cream Dela DEET caramel chocolate don't need that
so first things first let's get this thing spun
up noise [Music]
I'm going to check this I'm not going to
put the do deche and spin it again no we're
good if you have a liquid or a sauce or
something that you want to distribute
into your ninja creamy don't run it on the
add in mix don't run it again don't spin it
again just spin it once like this and stir
it in it it distribute I find it distributes
those sauces way too sparingly so you actually
don't get any in there you don't get enough of
a swirl in there but hey that's just me right
get this out of the way let's get some dished
[Music]
up and just to finish off we're going to
take some valona Dulce chocolate which is
a caramel chocolate and grade that
over the top and let's do a [Music]
closeup so there we have coffee American style
ice cream using that 18% coffee cream UK single
cream same fat percentage same recipe we use
condensed milk for the sugar and the solids and
the milk solids non fat we added our extract and
then our corn syrup to give it that extra level
of mouth feel Perfection topped it with our DL
deetra Havana this loads of different Del delet
tray floating around use whatever one you like and
our valona delce which is a blonde chocolate it's
like a caramelized white milk chocolate hybrid
you don't have to do that but why not let's try
some and see how we got on I try not to swear
in my videos anymore people moan about it but
coffee ice cream is delicious it's different
flavor coffee to making one with you know
coffee beans or instant coffee whatever it's a
different kind of flavor I'm going to show you
how to make your own version of this which
actually gives you a slightly more rounded
natural coffee flavor but it's still excellent
to use so you got a really nice creamy coffee
ice cream with a doce deche puddle on
top and with that caramelized chocolate
man that's
good if you don't want to use the corn syrup
golden syrup inverted sugar in disc then just
don't just take it out it it just adds
another level of of finesse to your ninja
creamy recipes as we know a lot of them are
really crap I'm here to help you improve those
give this one a try it's it's always
morning when I do these how about 10 in the
morning I'm going to eat this whole
thing man that is good anyway don't
forget to like And subscribe
if you want to see what I do
with the armored version of this and
I will see you next week [Music] but